<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
  <title>Iconicompany</title>
  <link>https://iconicompany.com/blog</link>
  <description>Evolutionary HR System</description>
  
    <item>
      <title>People, AI Agents, and Robots: How the Structure of Labor is Changing</title>
      <link>https://iconicompany.com/en/blog/people-ai-agents-robots-future-of-work</link>
      <description>More than half of working time can be automated today. Why AI agents are becoming a key element of the future economy – and where the role of humans remains indispensable.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  
    <item>
      <title>DevOps for Startups: Moving Away from Vercel Without Complicating Things 🛠</title>
      <link>https://iconicompany.com/en/blog/startup-devops-dokploy</link>
      <description>How to get Vercel</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  
    <item>
      <title>Why Do We Need AI Agents at All?</title>
      <link>https://iconicompany.com/ru/blog/why-do-we-need-ai-agents</link>
      <description>The answer is simple: to move from a passive content generator to an active task performer</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  
    <item>
      <title>How IT Specialists Can Level Up Using Work Tasks</title>
      <link>https://iconicompany.com/en/blog/practical-it-training</link>
      <description>How can an IT specialist gain new experience without courses and training? Use work tasks! Choose a priority growth area, implement new knowledge in projects, break learning into steps, and track progress. Learn in small blocks, include learning in sprints, and share knowledge. This approach will accelerate development and increase your expertise.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  
    <item>
      <title>How We Help the Team Plan Sprints and Identify Bottlenecks in a Project</title>
      <link>https://iconicompany.com/en/blog/sprint-planning-quest-stop-method</link>
      <description>How sprint planning works at Iconicompany without strict control: the QUEST and STOP frameworks help the team identify bottlenecks, work autonomously, and grow.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  
    <item>
      <title>The Death of the Static Resume: Why the Future of Hiring Belongs to a Network of Digital Twins</title>
      <link>https://iconicompany.com/en/blog/digital-twins-ai-net</link>
      <description>Traditional resume databases are dead. This article explores the concept of a self-managing network where active AI agents (digital twins) replace obsolete PDF files, automating sourcing and pre-screening.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  
    <item>
      <title>tencent-calm-vector-matching-optimization.mdx</title>
      <link>https://iconicompany.com/en/blog/tencent-calm-vector-matching-optimization</link>
      <description></description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  
    <item>
      <title>A New Player in the Arena: Comparing MCP, A2A, and AGNTCY in the AI Agent Ecosystem</title>
      <link>https://iconicompany.com/en/blog/mcp-a2a-agntcy</link>
      <description>Comparing protocols and infrastructure for AI agents.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  
    <item>
      <title>Two Years of Success: Key Milestones and Future Plans</title>
      <link>https://iconicompany.com/en/blog/two-years-anniversary</link>
      <description>Today, May 23, 2024, our company turns two years old. During this time, we have reached significant heights, launched several successful fintech projects, became finalists and winners of the IIDF accelerator, and created our own marketplace for IT specialists. We are proud of our achievements and how far we have come in such a short time.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  
    <item>
      <title>Why We Are No Longer Just a Marketplace and Are Spinning Off SaaS</title>
      <link>https://iconicompany.com/en/blog/splitting-service-and-product-business</link>
      <description>Investor rejection can be the best business lesson. We thought we were a product startup, but the fund opened our eyes: we are a tech-enabled agency. In this article, we honestly break down our pivot case: how to escape the "hybrid model" trap and legally and operationally separate the service business from the SaaS product. Learn why trying to sit on two chairs lowers company valuation and how to turn criticism into a strategy for exponential growth.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  
    <item>
      <title>Comparative Analysis of Matching Algorithms in a Self-Improving Loop</title>
      <link>https://iconicompany.com/en/blog/evolution-ai-hr</link>
      <description>The article examines an approach to building an autonomous recruitment system capable of continuous self-learning without human annotation. An architecture is proposed where various ranking algorithms (Vector Search based on fine-tuned embeddings, MLP, Batch Neural Networks) compete to maximize quality metrics. A Large Language Model (LLM) is used as the "Ground Truth" benchmark and generator of training pairs, evaluating the semantic fit of "specialist-vacancy" pairs. The results of a comparative analysis of the correlation between algorithm predictions and LLM evaluations are presented, demonstrating the superiority of fine-tuned embeddings over complex neural network classifiers in limited sample conditions.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  
    <item>
      <title>Successful Collaboration Between "YaCompany" LLC and the University of Artificial Intelligence</title>
      <link>https://iconicompany.com/en/blog/neural-university-cooperation</link>
      <description>The project aimed to automate the job matching process for candidates based on JSON resume analysis. This solution not only simplified the resume submission process but also significantly accelerated the selection of relevant vacancies, made possible by advanced AI technologies, including GPT models for data analysis.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  
    <item>
      <title>OCR and VLM 2026: Who Leads in Document Recognition</title>
      <link>https://iconicompany.com/en/blog/best-llm-for-ocr-2026</link>
      <description>An overview of modern OCR and Visual-Language Models (VLM) for document processing: DeepSeek-OCR 2, Step3-VL-10B, PaddleOCR-VL-1.5, and GLM-OCR.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  
    <item>
      <title>Люди, ИИ-агенты и роботы: как меняется структура труда</title>
      <link>https://iconicompany.com/ru/blog/people-ai-agents-robots-future-of-work</link>
      <description>Более половины рабочего времени уже сегодня может быть автоматизировано. Почему ИИ-агенты становятся ключевым элементом экономики будущего — и где роль человека остаётся незаменимой.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  
    <item>
      <title>DevOps для стартапов: уходим от Vercel, но не усложняем жизнь 🛠</title>
      <link>https://iconicompany.com/ru/blog/startup-devops-dokploy</link>
      <description>Как получить удобство Vercel без vendor lock-in: self-hosted PaaS, VPS и простой CI/CD для MVP</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  
    <item>
      <title>Зачем нам вообще AI-агенты?</title>
      <link>https://iconicompany.com/ru/blog/why-do-we-need-ai-agents</link>
      <description>Ответ прост: чтобы перейти от пассивного генератора контента к активному исполнителю задач</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  
    <item>
      <title>Как прокачать новый опыт ИТ-специалисту с помощью рабочих задач</title>
      <link>https://iconicompany.com/ru/blog/practical-it-training</link>
      <description>Как ИТ-специалисту прокачать новый опыт без курсов и тренингов? Используй рабочие задачи! Выбери приоритетную зону роста, внедряй новые знания в проекты, разбивай изучение на шаги и следи за прогрессом. Учись небольшими блоками, включай изучение в спринты и делись знаниями. Такой подход ускорит развитие и повысит твою экспертность.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  
    <item>
      <title>Как мы помогаем команде планировать спринты и находить узкие места в проекте</title>
      <link>https://iconicompany.com/ru/blog/sprint-planning-quest-stop-method</link>
      <description> Как в Iconicompany планируют спринты без жёсткого контроля: методики QUEST и STOP помогают команде находить узкие места, работать автономно и развиваться.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  
    <item>
      <title>Смерть статического резюме: Почему будущее найма — за сетью цифровых двойников</title>
      <link>https://iconicompany.com/ru/blog/digital-twins-ai-net</link>
      <description>Традиционные базы резюме мертвы. Статья раскрывает концепцию самоуправляемой сети, где активные AI-агенты (цифровые двойники) заменяют устаревшие PDF-файлы, автоматизируя поиск и пре-скрининг.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  
    <item>
      <title>От косинусного сходства к «энергии» смыслов: как исследование Tencent CALM меняет правила игры в ИИ-подборе</title>
      <link>https://iconicompany.com/ru/blog/tencent-calm-vector-matching-optimization</link>
      <description>В статье анализируется исследование лаборатории Tencent — архитектура CALM (Continuous Autoregressive Language Models) — и её потенциал для трансформации процессов HR-теха. Мы рассматриваем ограничения традиционного косинусного сходства при сопоставлении навыков и предлагаем альтернативные методы: использование энергетической оценки (Energy Score), создание устойчивого латентного пространства через вариационную регуляризацию и повышение семантической пропускной способности векторов. Статья описывает путь от «хрупких» эмбеддингов к высокоточным системам автоматизированного матчинга талантов.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  
    <item>
      <title>Новый игрок на арене: Сравниваем MCP, A2A и AGNTCY в экосистеме AI-агентов</title>
      <link>https://iconicompany.com/ru/blog/mcp-a2a-agntcy</link>
      <description>Сравнение протоколов и инфраструктуры для AI-агентов.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  
    <item>
      <title>Два года успеха: Итоги и планы на будущее</title>
      <link>https://iconicompany.com/ru/blog/two-years-anniversary</link>
      <description>Сегодня, 23 мая 2024 года, нашей компании исполняется два года. За это время мы достигли значительных высот, запустили несколько успешных финтех проектов, стали финалистами и победителями акселератора ФРИИ, а также создали собственный маркетплейс для ИТ специалистов. Мы гордимся своими достижениями и тем, как далеко смогли продвинуться за столь короткий срок.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  
    <item>
      <title>Почему мы перестаем быть просто маркетплейсом и выделяем SaaS</title>
      <link>https://iconicompany.com/ru/blog/splitting-service-and-product-business</link>
      <description>Отказ инвестора может стать лучшим бизнес-уроком. Мы считали себя продуктовым стартапом, но фонд открыл нам глаза: мы — технологичное агентство. В статье честно разбираем кейс пивота: как выйти из ловушки «гибридной модели», юридически и операционно разделить сервисный бизнес и SaaS-продукт. Узнайте, почему попытка усидеть на двух стульях снижает оценку компании и как превратить критику в стратегию кратного роста.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  
    <item>
      <title>Сравнительный анализ алгоритмов матчинга в самообучающемся контуре</title>
      <link>https://iconicompany.com/ru/blog/evolution-ai-hr</link>
      <description>В статье рассматривается подход к построению автономной системы подбора персонала, способной к непрерывному самообучению без участия человека-разметчика. Предложена архитектура, где различные алгоритмы ранжирования (векторный поиск на базе fine-tuned embeddings, MLP, Batch-нейросети) конкурируют за максимизацию метрики качества. В качестве эталона ("Ground Truth") и генератора обучающих пар используется Большая Языковая Модель (LLM), оценивающая семантическое соответствие пар «специалист-вакансия». Приводятся результаты сравнительного анализа корреляции предсказаний алгоритмов с оценками LLM, демонстрирующие превосходство дообученных эмбеддингов над сложными нейросетевыми классификаторами в условиях ограниченной выборки.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  
    <item>
      <title>Успешное сотрудничество ООО "ЯКомпания" и университета искусственного интеллекта</title>
      <link>https://iconicompany.com/ru/blog/neural-university-cooperation</link>
      <description>Целью проекта была автоматизация процесса подбора вакансий для кандидатов на основе анализа резюме в формате JSON. Это решение позволило не только упростить процесс подачи резюме, но и значительно ускорить подбор релевантных вакансий, что стало возможным благодаря использованию передовых технологий искусственного интеллекта, в том числе моделей GPT для анализа данных.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  
    <item>
      <title>OCR и VLM 2026: кто лидирует в распознавании документов</title>
      <link>https://iconicompany.com/ru/blog/best-llm-for-ocr-2026</link>
      <description>Обзор современных моделей OCR и визуально-языковых моделей (VLM) для работы с документами: DeepSeek-OCR 2, Step3-VL-10B, PaddleOCR-VL-1.5 и GLM-OCR.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  
</channel>
</rss>